# Kristen Kulha

Software Developer



941.914.3187



Kristen.m.kulha@gmail.com



Linkedin.com/in/kristenkulha



Github.com/kristenmarie

# **EDUCATION**

# Seattle Central College

BS Computer Science
2014-Ongoing
VP Computer Science Club
Robotics Club
Learned Computer Science concepts
such as data structures and algorithms
while using Python and Java.

## **Epicodus**

Ruby on Rails Track
July 2017 – December 2017
Gained hands-on experience coding and built numerous full-stack web applications with Ruby on Rails and Angular/JavaScript. Strong focus on TDD, pair programming and writing maintainable code.

## SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby,

HTML, CSS, SQL

Frameworks: Angular, Rails, ¡Query,

ActiveRecord, Sinatra

**Testing:** RSpec, Capybara, Jasmine,

Istanbul, Karma

Other: Git, Heroku, Communication

## **PROFILE**

10 years of customer service experience and enjoys working on a team. I recently graduated from Epicodus, where I gained hands-on experience coding and built full-stack web applications from scratch. I am ready to roll up my sleeves to tackle challenging opportunities where I could make an impact with my backend coding skills.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

ChalkDoc 2018

• My internship team is working on a magic problem generator. It will allow users to define any equa they like, set any parameters for that equation, and generate an unlimited number of problems meet those parameters.

#### INTERN

The Good Mood Creators 2015-2017

- Head of Xbox certification where I analyzed and tested the software before launch
- Traveled with the team to demonstrate and share the product with international markets

#### **ASSISTANT MANAGER**

Cherry Street Coffee House 2012-2016

- Started as a barista and promoted to assistant store manager
- Strategically assigned tasks and responsibilities to team members that utilized their strengths
- Proactive problem solver and comfortable with taking the lead and initiating hard conversations

## **PROJECTS**

## EAT UP (GROUP)

An Angular 2 Web Application that allows users to create an account and search for restaurants by cuisine type within a specified city and add them to a favorites list.

- I was responsible for integrating the Google Map into the front end and displaying data, utilizing Google Places as well as storing user data in Firebase.
- Google Maps, JavaScript, Angular, Firebase
- GitHub Repo: https://github.com/MegOlson/eat-up

## LOOKING FOR GROUP (INDEPENDENT)

Single handedly created a full-stack Ruby on Rails web application that engages communities of passionate tabletop gamers.

- Ruby on Rails, RSpec, PostgreSQI, Google Maps API, Devise, HTML, CSS, Simple Calendar, Private Pub, Faye
- GitHub Repo: https://github.com/kristenmarie/looking\_for\_group

## ÍSLENDINGASÖGUR (INDEPENDENT)

A currently ongoing passion project (video game) that teaches users the Icelandic sagas though an interactive two dimensional role playing game.

~ ... <u>~...</u> .